Guide to the John R. Post Collection of Lawrence Clark Powell Material
Department of Special Collections
John R. Post collection of Lawrence Clark Powell material
1919-1998
M1419
John R. Post
11 linear ft
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
The collection contains specially-printed keepsakes, broadsides, magazines, photographs, tapes and cds, and other miscellaneous items either written by, or about, Lawrence Clark Powell, UCLA librarian and "bookman."
Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mr. and Mrs. John R. Post, 2003. Accession 2004-029.
Scope and Content of Collection
This collection includes: 1. Special printings of limited editions for use as keepsakes, personal gifts, etc.; 2. Broadsides, including a special series of 12, 1953-1958, printed for Powell, as well as 7 others using quotations from various literary figures. 3. Magazines (Arizona Highways, New Mexico Magazine, and Westways) with articles by Powell. Also Hoja Volante, a publication of the Zamorano Club of Los Angeles contains articles by Powell. 4. UCLA publications for the libraries including prefaces, forewords, and essays by Powell. 5. Miscellaneous articles by Powell in diverse journals, reprints, magazines, newspaper clippings, book publication announcements, book club flyers and book dealer catalogues. 6. Audio tapes, CD's and video. The tapes and CD's were recorded by Powell in his home in Tucson, AZ, 1997-1998. The video is about Henry Miller with a small segment with Powell. 7. Photographs, seven prints, 1950-1981 and nd.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Powell, Lawrence Clark, 1906-; Post, John R., collector.; American literature--20th century.
Container List
- Series 1: Special Printings
  - The Manuscripts of D. H. Lawrence 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Compiled by Lawrence Clark Powell
  - H. Clark Powell 1939 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    edited by Lawrence Powell
  - D. H. Lawrence and his critics. A chronological Excursion in Bio-Bibliography 1940 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Reprint form The Colophon; 2 copies, one inscribed
  - A Little Tour of Vezelay 1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    For Gertrude Clark Powell, a family gift on her 70th birthday.
  - Exhibiton of Western Books 1941 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Rounce and Coffin Club
  - A Persian Pastorale 1945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Pronted by L.C.P.
  - Casanova 1948 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Signed by L.C.P.
  - A Landmark Gone 1949 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Note by L.C.P.
  - Recollections of a Bookseller 1950 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    500 copy run
  - Robinson Jeffers 1951 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Reprint of lecture
  - An Obstinate Exile 1951 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Laurie E. Lee
  - City of the Sun 1952 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Laurie Lee
  - Essences of Britain 1952 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Reprint, Annual of the Antiquarian Booksellers' Assn
  - Librarian on Leave 1952 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Letters to staff at UCLA
  - Vroman's of Pasadena 1953 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Comments, published on opening of new store
  - To Newbury to Buy an Old Book 1953 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Autographed, private printing
  - A Man Named Dobie 1954 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Printed for first joint meeting of Zamorano Club and the Los Angeles Westerners, 150 copy run
  - Sky, Sun and Water: The Southwest of Frederick Webb Hodge 1954 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Address given at the Zamorano Club in honor of Hodge's 89th birthday
  - Robinson Jeffers and Occidental 1955 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Forward by L.C.P,
  - The Roxburghe Club of San Francisco; The Zamorano Club of Los Angeles 1955 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    The Roster
  - The Published Writings of R. Wagner 1955 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Forward by L. C. P.; signed by L.C.P.
  - The Books of Bookmen 1955 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    "The Librarian'" L.C.P.
  - The First Book Printed in Guatemala in the Year 1663 1956 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Bookclub of Califonia publication chapter
  - Los Angeles Public Library Celebrates it's millionth Book 1956 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Comments delivered at Los Angeles Breakfast Club, May 16, 1956; 2 copies
  - At the Heart of the Matter 1957 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Comments delivered at Friends of the UCLA Library 20th anniversary banquet, January 23, 1957
  - The Language of the Heart 1957 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Signed by L.C.P,
  - Farewells to Phil Townsend Hanna 1957 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Comments delivered at memorial service, June 4, 1957
  - The Islandia World of Austin Wright 1957 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Talk delivered Zamoran Club, April 1957
  - In Memorium Tributes at the Bier of Henry Raup Wagner 1957 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Comments delivered at memorial service, April 1, 1957
  - Landscapes and Bookscapes of California 1958 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Address to the Friends of the Bancroft Library. May 4, 1958
  - The Springs of Clitumnus 1958 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    Printed for L.C.P,
  - ...."and Brown" 1959 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    London
  - The Roots of Regional Literature 1959 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Lecture delivered at New Mexico Highlands University, June 29, 1959
  - Act of Enchantment 1961 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Lecture delivered at New Mexico State University, signed by Jack Rittenhouse
  - Act of Enchantment 1961 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Lecture delivered at New Mexico State University, November 19, 1960
  - Robinson Jeffers 1962 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Produced for joint meeting of the Zamorano Club and Roxburghe Club, September, 1962; L.C.P. pp 28-29
  - Which Entrance to Library Service ? 1962 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Selected Bibliography, Notes on Certain Essays, copiled by Wm. Emerson Hinchcliff
  - The Prospect Before Us 1963 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Address for Fiftieth Anniversary of the Book Club of CA
  - An Islandial on the Islands 1963 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Reprint, introduction by L.C.P. for the Friends of the UCLA Library
  - In Search of Spring 1963 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Inscription by L.C.P.
  - H. H. C. (Harold Haines Clark) 1964 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Eulogy spoken by L.C.P., Cornwall-on-Hudson, NY
  - L. L. L. [The Three L's [Life, Landscape, and Literature] 1964 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Address at the Grolier Club of New York, January 23,1964
  - Viva Wagner 1964 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Remarks delivered at Memorial Award Dinner, CA Historical Society, September 25, 1964
  - Three Who Met the Challenge: Joseph F. Wheeler, Lawrence Clark Powell, Frances Clarke Sayers 1965 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Speech delivered by Edwin Castagna, Annual Congress for Librarians, February 22, 1964
  - Make Mine a Small One 1965 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Reprint, essay published in NY Times, December 6, 1964
  - Ralph MacKnight Smith 1965 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Words spoken at memorial, Santa Monica, CA, March 23, 1965
  - C. B. E. L. {The Making of the Cambridge Biblography] George Watson 1965 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Reprint of lecture given at UCLA, December 8, 1964, foreword by L.C.P.
  - Come Hither: Papers on Children's Literature and Librarianship 1966 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Farewell meeting remarks for Frances Clarke Sayers, UCLA, ed. by L.C.P.
  - Musical Blood Brothers: Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart, Franz Josef Hayden 1966 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Addresses given to the Zamorano Club
  - Bibloiographers of the Golden State 1967 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Lecture, given at UCLA,and UC-Berkeley
  - The Example of Miss Edith M. Coulter 1969 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    California Library Association Keepsake Number 8
  - The Untarnished Gold --The Immutable Treasure: A Report On A Book-In-Progress 1970 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Keepsake Number 3 in a series, Library Associates of the University Library, Davis
  - Bookmen and their Brothels: Recollections of Los Angeles in the 1930's 1970 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Address by Ward Richie given to the Zamorano Club (L.C.P. not
  - H.H. H.: The Three H's [Hands, Head, Heart] 1971 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Speech given at University of Zagreb, 1966, reprinted for UCLA School of Library Science
  - Silverado Squatters: Robert Louis Stevenson 1971 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Reprint for Norman and Charlotte Strouse, used as a Christmas greeting
  - The Western Books Exhibition, Rounce and Coffin Club, LA 1972 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Catalog, L.C.P. plate 30
  - Bartok: A Memoir by Yehudi Menuhin 1973 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Postscript by L.C.P.
  - Quince, etc.: Exposing the several disguises of Ward Ritchie, poet, with a remark by Lawrence Powell 1974 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Autographed, no. 8 of about 50
  - Charles F. Lummis: a Bibliography 1977 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Mary A. Sarber author, foreword by L.C.P., 2 copies
  - A Talk Honoring Lawrence Clark Powell: On the Occasion of his 70th Birthday 1977 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    Bert M. Fireman, author; inscribed by L.C.P.
  - Great Constellations 1977 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    A talk given in El Paso, TX, honoring Jose Cisneros, Carl Hertzog, Peter Hurd, and Tom Lea
  - A Keepsake Presented in Honor of Claire Morrill, Octogenarian 1978 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Letter to Claire Morrill at back of publication by L.C.P.
  - The Enchanted Couple 1979 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    Address, given on occassion of award presentation to L.C.P. by Gleeson Library Associates
  - Ward Ritchie Printer: A Seventy-Fifth Birthday Salute on June 15, 1980 1980 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    "I Call Him Richman," by L.C.P., publication accompanied retrospective exhibit of Ritchie's work, UCLA.
  - Indian Summer [Sir William Rothenstein] 1980 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Keepsake from L.C.P. for the 15th biennial of Zamorano and Roxeburghe clubs, SF
  - A Remembrance: for the 50th anniversary meeting of the Rounce and Coffin Club 1981 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Foreword by L.C.P.
  - Goethe's Dream of Sicily 1982 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Private printing for L.C.P. to give to members of Tucson Literary Club.
  - The Mystique of Printing: A Half Century of Books designed by Ward Ritchie 1984 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Foreword by L.C.P., autographed
  - Remembering Ed Castgna 1984 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Printed for L.C.P. for 17th biennial Zamorano-Roxeburghe meeting; foreword and interview by L.C.P.
  - A Good Place to Begin 1986 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Address at fundraiser for LA Public Library, 88th Conference of Clalifornia Library Assn
  - Return to the Heartland: Reminiscences of Texas Books and Book People 1987 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    DeGolyer Library Keepsake Number Two
  - Growing Up With Lawrence Clark Powell 1987 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    The 1986 Coulter Lecture, given by Ward Ritchie
  - That Kitty Colette 1988 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Fay Ellen Powell, author; one of 200 case bound copies
  - Transpacific 1966: Travel Notes from a Foreign Land 1988 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Presented by L.C.P. at the 19th Biennial Reunion of the Zamarano-Roxeburghe Clubs; autographed
  - The Rise of Los Angeles as an American Bibliographical Center 1989 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    The 1988 Coulter Lecture, given by Kevin Starr; preface by L.C.P.
  - Z to A Illyria to Cambria 1990 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Presented by L.C.P. at the 20th Biennial Reunion of the Zamarano-Roxeburghe Clubs; autographed
  - A Tale of Lissadell 1992 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Presented by L.C.P. at the 21th Biennial Reunion of the Zamarano-Roxeburghe Clubs
  - Some Writings About Los Angeles 1992 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Reprint of LA Times article,
  - The 55th Annual Western Books Exhibiton 1995 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    L.C.P. "The Holly and the Fleece" featured on p.10
  - Win Some Lose Some 1995 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Reprint of essay delivered April 16, 1979 to the Tucson Literary Club, presneted at 1995 meeting.
  - The Road to Swarthmore 1996 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    A Thanksgiving offereing to friends, on the occasion of L.C.P.'s 90th birthday
  - Fashioned in Friendship 1996 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Tribute to L.C.P. and Ward Ritchie, 90th Birthday Exhibition in celebration of L.C.P., University of Arizona Library
  - A Southland Bohemia [Ward Ritchie] 1996 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Ward Ritchie, author; autographed by Vance Gerry
  - Western Books the 56th Annual Exhibition 1997 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    "The Road to Swarthmoor" featured on p.34
- Series 2: Magazines
  - Westways 1934 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    "Robinson Jeffers on Life and Letters," Article by L.C.P.
  - Westways 4/1/1958 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    The Grande Del Norte
  - Westways 8/1/1958 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Photographer of the Southwest
  - Westways 2/1/1959 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    Fifty Books of the Half Century
  - Westways 11/1/1962 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    Western Books and Writers
  - Westways 8/1/1963 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    Book Hunter in Britain
  - Westways 10/1/1963 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    Good Reading About the Desert
  - Westways 1/1/1966 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    Books of the West
  - Westways 2/1/1966 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Arizona Highways 9/1/1963 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Northland Press
  - Westways 3/1/1966 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Westways 5/1/1966 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Westways 6/1/1966 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Westways 7/1/1966 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Westways 8/1/1966 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Westways 9/1/1966 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Westways 10/1/1966 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Westways 3/1/1967 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Westways 4/1/1967 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Westways 6/1/1967 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Westways 7/1/1967 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Westways 8/1/1967 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Westways 9/1/1967 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Westways 10/1/1967 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Westways 11/1/1967 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Westways 12/1/1967 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Westways 1/1/1968 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Westways 2/1/1968 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Westways 3/1/1968 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Westways 4/1/1968 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Westways 5/1/1968 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Two Years Before the Mast
  - Westways 6/1/1968 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    The Mountains of California
  - Westways July, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Pomona Article
  - Westways 8/1/1968 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    The Silverado Squatters
  - Westways 10/1/1968 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    The Splendid Idle Forties
  - Westways 11/1/1968 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Give Your Heart to the Hawks
  - Westways 12/1/1968 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    To A God Unknown
  - Westways 1/1/1969 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    California Coast Trails
  - Westways 2/1/1969 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Remeniscencees of a Ranger
  - Westways 3/1/1969 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Farewell My Lovely
  - Westways 4/1/1969 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    The Cattle on a Thousand Hills
  - Westways 5/1/1969 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    McTeague
  - Westways 6/1/1969 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    The Luck of Roaring Camp
  - Westways 7/1/1969 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Roughing It
  - Westways 9/1/1969 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Martin Eden
  - Westways 10/1/1969 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Anza's California Expiditions
  - Westways 11/1/1969 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Death Valley in '49
  - Westways 12/1/1969 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    The Shirley Letters
  - New Mexico Magazine 2/1/1959 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    Round-up of the Waters
  - New Mexico Magazine 1/1/1960 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    50 Good Books About New Mexico
  - New Mexico Magazine 3/1/1962 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    First Lady of Letters: Erna Fergasson
  - New Mexico Magazine May-June 1974 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    Land of the Many Returns
  - Westways 1/1/1970 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    The Land of Sinshine
  - Westways 2/1/1970 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    The Wonders of the Colorado Desert
  - Westways 2/1/1970 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Westways 3/1/1970 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    The Vineyard
  - Westways 4/1/1970 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    Up and Down California
  - Westways 5/1/1970 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Mountaineering in the Sierra Nevada
  - Westways June 1970 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    California and the West
  - Westways 7/1/1970 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    The Journey of the Flame
  - Westways 8/1/1970 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Boy on Horseback
  - Westways 9/1/1970 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Oil!
  - Westways 10/1/1970 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Merton of the Movies
  - Westways 11/1/1970 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    The Day of the Locust
  - Westways 12/1/1970 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    After Many a Summer Die the Swan
  - Westways 2/1/1971 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    Coronado's Children
  - Westways 3/1/1971 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Dancing God
  - Westways 4/1/1971 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    Interlinear to Cabeza de Vaca
  - Westways May 19771 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    Commerce of the Praries
  - Westways 6/1/1971 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    The Desert Year
  - Westways 7/1/1971 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    Vanished Arizona
  - Westways 8/1/1971 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    Classic at Continent's End
  - Westways 9/1/1971 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    Sky Determines
  - Westways 10/1/1971 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    Adventures in Apache Country
  - Westways 11/1/1971 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    The Plumed Serpent
  - Westways 12/1/1971 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    Laughing Boy
  - Westways 1/1/1972 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    Wolf Song
  - Westways 2/1/1972 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    Death Comes to the Archbishop
  - Westways 3/1/1972 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    The Desert
  - Westways 4/1/1972 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    Henry Miller at Eighty
  - Westways 5/1/1972 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Massacre andVengeance in Apacheria
  - Westways 7/1/1972 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    When Teddy Went West
  - Westways 8/1/1972 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Winter of the Purple Page
  - Westways 10/1/1972 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Two for the Santa Fe Trail
  - Westways 11/1/1972 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    The Fathers of Primeria Alta
  - Westways 12/1/1972 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    A Land to Know, A West to love
  - Westways 1/1/1973 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Lady of Taos
  - Westways 5/1/1973 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Song of the Southwest
  - Westways 6/1/1973 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    The Mystique Endures
  - Westways 6/1/1973 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Westways 9/1/1973 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    A Nice Place to Visit
  - Westways 11/1/1973 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    A Letter From the Southwest
  - Westways 2/1/1974 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    A Valentine to Gertrude Stein
  - Westways 5/1/1974 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    Maynard Dixon's Painted Desert
  - Westways 5/1/1974 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Westways 7/1/1974 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    Personalities of the West My Bookseller
  - Westways 9/1/1974 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    A Yorkshire Man Wanders West
  - Westways 1/1/1975 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    Letter From the Southwest
  - Westways 3/1/1975 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    Letter from the Southwest
  - Westways 5/1/1975 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Westways 7/1/1975 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Westways 9/1/1975 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    Letter from the Souhwest
  - Westways 11/1/1975 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    Printing Was His Art
  - Westways 1/1/1976 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    To Visit Monterey
  - Westways 3/1/1976 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    Beyond the Bicentennial
  - Westways 7/1/1976 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    Youthful Sentiments / S. Pasadena
  - Westways 9/1/1976 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Westways 11/1/1976 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    A Librarian's Holiday
  - Westways 1/1/1978 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Westways 4/1/1978 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    A Letter from a Farther Southwest
  - Westways 6/1/1978 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Westways November 1978 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Westways 1/1/1979 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Westways 2/1/1979 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    An Editorial Thrust
  - Westways 4/1/1979 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Westways 8/1/1979 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Westways 10/1/1979 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Westways January 1980 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    A Doff to Don
  - Westways 3/1/1980 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Westways 5/1/1980 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Westways 7/1/1980 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Westways 8/1/1980 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    No Ordinary Man HenryMiller
  - Westways 9/1/1980 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Westways 11/1/1980 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Arizona Highways August 1956 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Books. Pinon nuts. and Shadows
  - Arizona Highways 2/1/1957 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Heart of the Southwest
  - Arizona Highways 6/1/1957 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    My Southwest; J. Frank Dobie of Texas
  - Arizona Highways 3/1/1958 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    A Southwestern Century
  - Arizona Highways 4/1/1959 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    With Books in My Baggage
  - Arizona Highways 8/1/1960 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Oasis of Books
  - Arizona Highways November 1961 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    Winter Days with Martha Summerhayes
  - Arizona Highways 12/1/1971 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    A Tribute to a Mere Magazine by a Great Man
  - Arizona Highways 9/1/1972 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    Exploring Arizona's Literary Trails
  - Arizona Highways 3/1/1974 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    The Deseert as Dwelled On
  - Arizona Highways 4/1/1975 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    Fifty Years of Treasure
  - Arizona Highways 10/1/1976 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    The Southwest - Photos by Ansel Adams
  - Arizona Highways 12/1/1976 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    Arizona: The Peaceful Land
  - Arizona Highways 1977 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    Arizona Highway: Desert Splendor
  - Arizona Highways 10/1/1982 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    The Desert Odyssey of John C. Van Dyke
  - Arizona Highways 4/1/1985 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    comment - pg. 88
  - Hoja Volante 5/1/1947 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    Hoja Volante --I Am An Escapist
  - Hoja Volante 8/1/1947 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    Cofessions of a Reconstructed Westerner
  - Hoja Volante 2/1/1958 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    Rabelasian Notes
  - Hoja Volante 5/1/1948 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    The Enjoyment of Joyce
  - Hoja Volante 8/1/1948 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    Hoja Volante
  - Hoja Volante 11/1/1949 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    Theme Time, the Place and the Book
  - Hoja Volante 2/1/1962 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    Mention of op. 1-8
  - Hoja Volante 5/1/1965 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    Mention of op.1
  - Hoja Volante 8/1/1965 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    Mention of op.pg. 2
  - Hoja Volante 11/1/1965 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    Mention of pg. 1
  - Hoja Volante #83 1966 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    Mention of; 1,2,4
  - Hoja Volante 5/1/1966 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    Mention of pg. 1,5,6,7
  - Hoja Volante 8/1/1966 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    L.C.P. Mention of pg. 1,2
  - Hoja Volante 11/1/1966 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    L.C.P. mention of pg.1,8
  - Hoja Volante 2/1/1962 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    L.C.P. mention of pg. 1
  - Hoja Volante 5/1/1967 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    L.C.P. mention of pg. 1,2
  - Hoja Volante August 1967 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    L.C.P. mention of pg.1
  - Hoja Volante 11/1/1967 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Hoja Volante 2/1/1968 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    L.C.P. mention of pg.1.2.3.4
  - Hoja Volante 8/1/1968 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    L.C.P. mention of pg. 1.4.5.6.7
  - Hoja Volante 11/1/1968 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    L.C.P,mention of pg. 1
  - Hoja Volante 2/1/1969 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Hoja Volante 5/1/1969 (Box 9, Folder 40)
    L.C.P. mention of pg.1,2
  - Hoja Volante 8/1/1969 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Hoja Volante 11/1/1969 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Hoja Volante February 1970 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Hoja Volante 5/1/1970 (Box 9, Folder 44)
    L.C.P. mention of 3,4,5
  - Hoja Volante 11/1/1970 (Box 9, Folder 45)
    L.C. P. mention of pg. 1
  - Hoja Volante 8/1/1979 (Box 9, Folder 46)
    L.C.P. Blue Train
- Series 3: Miscellaneous
  - Zamorano club announcement 1949 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    New Year celebration announcement
  - Book Collectors and Collecting libraries June 1950 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    California Library Bulletin
  - Books on the Land March 1950 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Books and People and the Earth on Which We Live February 1950 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    Wilson Library Bulletin
  - A California Bookman Abroad December 1950 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    Reprint, California Librarian
  - Librarianship in California September 1950 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    California Librarian
  - From Private Collector to Public Institution: The William Andrew Clark Library April 1950 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    Reprint,Library Quarterly